[The Heir]
[Episode 40]
Dear guests,
greetings.
The Li family's Sihe Ink you restored
shows exquisite craftsmanship,
comparable to what
the Li family's ancestors made,
revealing the Kuroda family's
extraordinary ink-making skill.
I am very impressed.
However,
this Sihe Ink is a treasure
made by the Li family's ancestors
during the Southern Tang Dynasty.
Since the Southern Tang Dynasty,
the Li family's ink has been refined
by later generations for hundreds of years
and flourished multiple times.
But you've still been studying
the ink-making techniques of our ancestors
from hundreds of years ago.
I think I don't need to say more
about the gap between them.
The guests have come from afar
and must be tired from the long journey.
As for the participation
in the election,
let's discuss it after you settle down.
Servants,
escort the guests
to the post house to take a rest.
Escort the Japanese guests
to the post house to rest.
We'll take our leave.
I, Li Zhen, pay my respects to you,
Your Highness.
Li Zhen,
do you have confidence in beating
the Kuroda family in the ink contest?
I wouldn't dare
to deceive you, Your Highness.
The ink item
the Kuroda family brought today
is indeed a long-lost treasure
of Huizhou Li Ink Workshop.
Nowadays,
not only Li Ink,
but even every workshop in Huizhou
is no match for them,
I'm afraid.
Are you saying
our Great Ming
can't win this ink contest?
If the contest were held today,
Li Ink would have to admit defeat.
But there's still some time
before the Tribute Ink selection.
It's still anyone's game
until the very end.
This is the aura
that the Head of the Workshop
leading Hui Ink should have.
Prefect He has arrived!
I, Luo Wenqian, pay my respects to you,
Your Highness.
Your Highness,
we've got a letter from General Yu.
You may rise.
Thank you, Your Highness.
Your Highness,
as our state
has lifted the ban on maritime trade,
merchant ships can sail from Yue Port
to the East and West Oceans.
Wherever they go,
trade and business prosper.
This time, only Japan was excluded
from the lifting of the ban.
General Yu found out that
the Japanese Kuroda family uses
the exchange of ink-making as an excuse
to participate
in the Tribute Ink selection this time.
Once they win,
they will ask our Great Ming
to grant their family trading rights
at the Yue Port.
This matter involves national policy.
Hence, he sent this letter to alert you,
Your Highness,
to pay more attention to it.
In addition,
the Kuroda family has always
colluded with the Japanese pirates.
General Yu is worried that the pirates
might take the chance to cause trouble,
so he specifically sent me here
for reinforcements,
just to take precautions.
My brother let the Kurodas participate
in the Tribute Ink selection this time
originally for the exchange
of ink-making skills.
We didn't expect the Kuroda family
to be up to something else.
Li Zhen,
if what General Yu said is true,
in this contest,
Hui Ink must emerge victorious.
Failure is not an option.
It concerns our Great Ming's
national maritime opening-up policy.
Do you understand?
Your Highness,
the Kuroda family came here this time,
claiming
that they learned from the ink
made by the Li family's ancestors.
But now,
they're using our family's long-lost ink
to provoke us.
Whether for the family or the state,
the Li family will not hesitate
to sacrifice everything.
Please rest assured, Your Highness.
Li Ink will do its utmost
to give His Majesty and you,
Your Highness, a satisfactory answer.
Good.
Then I will
wait and see.
There were so many people
and so many things going on that night.
I didn't get a chance
to talk to you properly.
Now that
you've returned to General Yu's command,
you finally have
your long-cherished wish fulfilled.
Congratulations.
I dare not have
any more long-cherished wishes.
I'm only repaying the favor.
For General Yu
and for you,
I'm doing the same.
Do you have any plans for the future?
I'm here on the General's orders
to guard against Japanese pirates
before the Tribute Ink selection.
Besides,
both professionally and privately,
I should assist you
to help Li Ink through this crisis.
So if you need anything from now on,
just let me know.
As for the future, I...
The Japanese pirates
haven't been subdued yet.
Be careful and stay safe.
I know.
Where are you going?
I'm going that way.
Well,
I'll go this way.
[Elegant Ink Hall]
[Sihe House]
[Yihousheng]
Sister.
Greetings, Sister.
Wenqian!
You are finally back!
Let me take a look at you.
You haven't changed.
You haven't changed at all,
still as impressive and handsome as ever.
I am so happy to see you.
Come on, take a look around.
Ever since you left,
I haven't changed a single thing
in Yihousheng—
not inside or outside.
I was waiting for you to come back.
Now that you're back,
it's time to return Yihousheng
to its owner.
Sister,
although Yihousheng hasn't changed,
to me,
it feels like a lifetime has passed.
So please don't return it to me.
It is just perfect for you, Sister,
to run Yihousheng.
Alright.
I will listen to you.
Come and take a seat.
Here, have some tea.
Thank you, Sister.
What's wrong?
Wenqian,
although you've been
fighting enemies on the battlefield,
do you know
that you carry less bloodthirsty aura
than you did 3 years ago?
I've grown up.
You really know me well, Sister.
Why didn't Jixiang come back with you?
The General was short-handed,
so I left him with the General.
That's good.
So what are your plans
now that you're back?
The General asked me to secretly
keep an eye on the Kuroda family.
I will fulfill
the General's entrustment first,
and then repair
our Luo family's ancestral hall
and place
my family's memorial tablets inside.
Have you seen your aunt?
My aunt
cried for quite a while,
but she told me,
"Wenqian,
in this world,
there is no longer Luo Mengzhen,
but only Ugly Granny Li."
Fate is so cruel.
The dead are gone,
but the living struggle to find peace.
It is true for your aunt,
and isn't it the same for you and Zhen?
Over the past 3 years,
every time you wrote,
every line was filled
with concern for Zhen.
I think
Zhen is not the kind of girl who is
easily trapped by worldly prejudices.
Since you can't let her go,
and you are now in the clear,
why don't you just say it outright,
court her openly, and win her back?
Sister,
actually, I have seen Zhen.
I knew when I came back this time,
I would definitely see her.
So I prepared a lot of things
I wanted to say to her.
But at the very moment,
I just couldn't say a single word.
Our Luo family
and the Li family...
Now, I only wish I could
protect her by her side
and keep her safe for a lifetime.
That'd be enough for me.
I dare not ask for anything else.
It's hot. Be careful.
It's ready. Come on.
Grandfather.
Redo it.
Let's try again.
Grandfather.
Take a break.
No rush.
Let's take a rest and try again later.
We've tried so many times.
Why can't I master
the precise method
of making the Sihe Ink's lampblack?
I just...
I really...
Uncle Jingdong!
Jingdong.
Why are you laughing?
Don't you guys find it weird?
The Sihe Ink brought by the Kuroda family
is almost identical
to our Li family's Sihe Ink,
whether in luster
or oiliness.
It is strange, indeed.
The Sihe Ink our Li family holds has
a history of at least hundreds of years.
But the Kuroda family's Sihe Ink is new!
It's no more than 10 years old, I guess?
Even if they are both of supreme quality,
there should
still be an obvious difference!
I once heard from an ink merchant
that Japan has
an extremely low production of ink,
so it's much easier for them
to find thousand-year-old pine timber
than it is for us.
So I think
the problem might lie in the pine timber.
No wonder.
The Li family Sihe Ink was
made by our ancestors
hundreds of years ago.
Back then, they made ink
by burning pine timber for lampblack.
There weren't many ink makers.
It was easy to find pine timber hundreds or
even over 1,000 years old in the mountains.
But since the Song Dynasty,
the ink industry has flourished.
The usage of pine timber in Huizhou
has increased gradually.
For the pine timber we're using today,
even the best is less than 100 years old.
Mr. Dongtu once thought of the same thing.
It's exactly because
Hui Ink prospered
that the pine forests
ended up getting depleted.
That explains it.
I thought it was
because of my lack of talent.
I took that slap for nothing.
In this case,
we are not completely at a disadvantage.
The difficulty in finding
thousand-year-old pine timber is one thing.
Even if we have it,
we would just barely
tie with them.
We still stand no chance of winning.
It's fine.
In this case,
let's just surpass our predecessors.
[Chen]
Does the problem
lie in the lampblack or the glue?
Father,
don't worry.
I will go try again.
The day of the Tribute Ink selection is
drawing close.
We still haven't figured out a single way
to compete with the Kuroda family.
How can I not worry?
Indeed.
Father.
If our Chen Ink can't beat them,
there's still Li Ink, Pan Ink,
and ink from Xiuning and Yi County.
The Kuroda family won't succeed.
The Kuroda family has
come in full force this time.
Even we are having a hard time
dealing with them,
let alone the others.
Besides,
the Tribute Ink selection this year
is not just about personal reputation,
but the pride of Hui Ink.
After all, I am one
of the Five Ink-making Grandmasters.
I am supposed to shoulder
this responsibility.
Third Master,
Young Master,
Miss Li Zhen invited you two
to Sibao Restaurant,
asking to discuss
a weighty matter with you.
Elders,
I invited you all here today
to inform you that
Li Ink will make Liuhe (Sixfold Mixing) Ink
to challenge the Kuroda family.
-Liuhe Ink?
There's no way!
How is that possible?
Every round of glue-mixing
in ink-making
just adds a level of difficulty.
Sihe (Fourfold Mixing) Ink is
already excellent.
Realizing sixfold mixing
can only be harder.
Manager Zhen.
Eighth Master Li.
How confident are you in making Liuhe Ink?
Elder,
I can't say how confident I am.
But for the Kuroda family's ink,
aside from its exquisite craftsmanship,
it also excels
because of its superior raw materials.
Since it is almost impossible for us
to outdo them on materials,
we must make a kind of ink
that is better than theirs
in craftsmanship.
Only then can we have a chance of winning.
Before this Sihe Ink,
no one ever thought
that ink could be made
with fourfold mixing.
But since our predecessors
could create this Sihe Ink craft,
why can't we,
who are standing on their shoulders,
take things one step further
and try to realize sixfold mixing
to make up for the deficiency in materials
and create an ink that surpasses Sihe Ink,
defeating the Kuroda family?
Well said!
Third Grandfather.
-Girl.
-Welcome.
Well said.
Third Master Chen.
-Uncle Junshan.
-Third Grandfather Chen.
-Third Master Chen.
-Sit down, please.
Everyone, please be seated.
Please sit down.
You heard it all?
Yes, I heard the whole speech.
To go one step further
than our predecessors,
this is a good idea.
Jinshui,
I have never thought you and the Li family
were outdoing me and my family.
But you have
such an excellent granddaughter.
I have to admit it.
Before coming here, I kept thinking
that among all the ink makers in Huizhou,
I am the oldest,
and I must grit my teeth
and shoulder the responsibility
for the younger generations.
But after hearing what this girl said,
I feel that she's
outdoing me.
She's indeed outdoing me.
If Liuhe Ink is successfully made,
it'll truly be a great achievement
combining all the existing techniques
and will surely be a masterpiece
to be handed down for generations.
Jinshui,
Chen Ink will admit defeat this time.
However, girl.
Time is running out.
To make Liuhe Ink is
no longer just the Li family's business.
If you run into any difficulties,
just feel free to tell me
and everyone here.
Third Grandfather,
you came at the right time.
Zhen was just about to ask you
for a favor.
What do you want me to help you with?
To make Liuhe Ink, glue-blending
is of the greatest significance.
I know Uncle Junshan is the best at it.
So, I would like to borrow him from you.
To blend glue, he has to enter
your Li family's ink-mixing area.
Aren't you afraid our Chen family
might steal your techniques?
Third Grandfather, you are joking again.
I want to make this Liuhe Ink, which also
carries the meaning of harmony
between heaven, earth, and people.
Today, I invited all the elders here
not only to inform everyone
that the Li family
will try to make this Liuhe Ink
but also to ask for everyone's assistance.
Let's unite all families
and make this Liuhe Ink.
Harmony between heaven, earth, and people.
This line is a good omen.
Junshan,
don't bring shame to our Chen family.
Yes.
Thank you, Third Grandfather.
Thank you, Uncle Junshan.
Don't mention it.
Miss Li,
although Pan Ink has declined now,
it was as famous as Li Ink
hundreds of years ago.
If Li Ink needs it,
I am willing to offer
the Pan family's heirloom manuscript
to help you make Liuhe Ink.
Good.
Nice.
Ruogu.
Sit down.
Sit down, please.
Craftsmen must first sharpen their tools
to do a job perfectly.
Our Xi family has nothing else
but a set of stone mortar and pestle
passed down for generations.
They can make the ink paste smoother,
and the produced ink blacker and shinier.
Just feel free to take them
if you need any.
-Great.
-Nice.
I'd like to express my gratitude
to you all
on behalf of Li Ink.
Girl,
don't just get excited.
For this Tribute Ink selection,
I'm giving you this one.
Next time,
I will definitely do my best
to defeat you and your grandfather.
Jinshui,
dare you accept this challenge?
Yes, of course.
These two old pals.
No.
Try again.
Yes.
Jinshui,
they can come in handy.
They're valuable items.
Grandfather.
Third Grandfather Chen.
Come and check out this soot.
It's done!
It's done.
[Luo's Ancestral Hall]
Father,
Wensong,
after the tragedy that struck Luo Ink,
I've finally brought you guys
back to the ancestral hall.
Today, as Luo Wenqian,
I can finally commemorate you
above board.
That year, Father and I
returned to Huizhou,
and we paid our respects
at this ancestral hall for the first time.
That day,
Father kept warning Wensong and me
never to ruin the reputation of Luo Ink.
But fate was cruel.
The one who ruined
the reputation of Luo Ink
and destroyed
the Luo family's legacy...
[Tablet of Hanzhang
of the Luo Family in Ming]
Father,
Wensong,
today, I have restored
the Luo family's ancestral hall
in order
to start anew.
If you two
can hear me in heaven,
please help me
atone
for our family's sins,
and please bless the Luo family
to revive one day.
Aunt,
are you
really not going in to take a look?
This is the Luo family's ancestral hall.
I am now Ugly Granny Li.
I am not one of the Luos.
Why should I enter
the Luo family's ancestral hall?
But after you pass away...
When I die,
Doggie will handle
my funeral affairs.
You
don't need to worry about me.
I see.
However,
be it Luo Mengzhen in the past
or today's Ugly Granny Li,
you will always be my aunt.
Our Luo family's ink craftsmanship
has been passed down for decades.
If these techniques
really fade away
with the Luo family's decline,
it would be a real pity.
But I know ink is your lifelong passion,
and you are
the only successor of the Luo family's
craftsmanship left in the world.
I have a presumptuous request.
I want to revive Luo Ink.
It doesn't need anything grand,
nor does it need a big storefront.
I just want to
focus on studying ink-making with you
to atone
for our Luo family's
past sins.
Everything in the world
rises and falls according to fate.
Why dwell on
the loss
of one family's ink-making legacy?
When your father
committed such an evil deed,
Luo Ink was already
doomed to fall.
Luo Mengzhen
already died in that fire long ago.
Why do you insist?
I grew up seeing my father, you,
and my brother
focus entirely on studying
ink-making techniques.
Just the thought
that Luo Ink's techniques
are about to be lost
makes me really sad.
The techniques of ink-making
are for people to use.
As long as someone is still using,
studying, and innovating them,
the techniques of Luo Ink
will never be lost.
The Luo family
used to hurt the Li family.
Now,
the Li family is having
an ink contest with the Kuroda family,
bearing the responsibilities and hopes
of the entire Huizhou ink industry.
These are
the manuscripts and ink recipes
of Luo Ink I've compiled over the years.
Take them
and give them to Miss Li Zhen
to help the Li family in some way.
This is the only way
to atone for the Luo family's sins.
From now on,
Luo Ink
will be integrated into Li Ink.
As long as Li Ink exists,
Luo Ink
will not disappear.
These are our Luo family's ink recipes?
[Collection of Luo Ink's Craftsmanship]
These really are
our Luo family's ink recipes.
Let me thank you
on behalf of Zhen.
Wenqian.
Zhen is a good girl.
I know you like her.
But in my opinion,
you two are not meant to be together.
Decades ago,
I was just like her,
full of passion and hope.
But in the end, it all came to nothing.
All came to nothing.
These manuscripts and ink recipes
are not only my atonement
on behalf of Luo Ink,
but they also carry my own wish.
I want to see her
go higher and further
on this path
of ink-making.
Are you okay?
You got burned?
I'm fine.
♪ Raindrops fall on
the moss-covered stone steps ♪
No way.
♪ With a bamboo knife,
you make the spring fade away ♪
It's still red and swollen.
Wait here. I'll get you some medicine.
♪ Last year's branches are still
hanging in the window ♪
♪ The tea left a stain on the sleeve ♪
Use this.
I've been carrying it
with me all the time.
♪ The wreathing smoke
gradually dissipated ♪
♪ Counting the games of our childhood ♪
♪ You lower your eyes
and count the rings of the tree ♪
♪ Scars meander like a stream ♪
♪ The ink-black distant mountains
resemble your eyes and brows ♪
♪ Amid the inky darkness,
it seems as though a galaxy is shifting ♪
♪ Lend me a bit of
the courage of a piece of pine resin ♪
In the past 3 years,
I have already restored the rouge ink.
♪ Amid the frost,
I sketch the unfinished prologue ♪
When you run out of this piece,
remember to go to the ink workshop
to get several new ones.
♪ The hazy, distant mountains
are just like you ♪
It works for both burns and cuts.
♪ A winding bridge
reflected in the water pavilion ♪
Then I would still not bear
to use this piece.
The ink you've restored
♪ If we are to part ways ♪
cannot compare to this one.
♪ Let the ink speak for me and say,
"Take care" ♪
Because only this piece
can not only heal wounds
but also heal the heart.
Why did you come so suddenly today?
These are our Luo family's
ink recipes.
My aunt asked me to give them to you.
Perhaps
they can be of help.
Granny asked you to give them to me?
These are the Luo Ink's recipes!
These are our Luo family's ink recipes.
But my aunt said
after that fire that year,
Luo Mengzhen already died.
Her surname is Li now.
But I know little about ink-making.
My ambition does not lie here.
But my aunt is right about one thing.
Only when
Luo Ink
is integrated into Li Ink one day
can it be passed down for hundreds
or thousands of years.
[Luo Ink's Techniques]
Please thank Granny for me.
My aunt also said
that although she hasn't seen you much
the past few years,
she knows you have been asking Doggie
to secretly send her money and items.
She feels very grateful to you.
But she also said that
she feels guilty towards the Li family
and must chant sutras
for the rest of her life
to pray for the Li family before Buddha.
My mother, grandfather,
and I
don't want to dwell on the past anymore.
Just let bygones
be bygones.
These years...
You must have had a tough time
the past few years in the southwest.
No.
After the general amnesty,
I rejoined the army
and returned to General Yu's side.
He got me a job,
so I've been doing okay.
But you,
you are amazing.
You have been fully supporting
Li Ink all these years.
And not just the Capital,
Sichuan, Shanxi, Henan, and Lingnan
all have your branches.
As expected of Manager Zhen.
So impressive.
You know it all?
I know it all.
I've kept in touch with Cuiqiao
these past few years.
But every time I wrote a letter,
I couldn't help
asking more about you.
Over the past 3 years,
Cuiqiao has also been helping me a lot.
I guess this was
also at your request.
Zhen.
Although I had been away for years,
I was always worried about you.
Wenqian,
right now, I'm only focused
on making Liuhe Ink perfectly.
I have no time for anything else.
Got it.
I got it.
I see.
I'll go check on the glue.
Can't ruin it again.
I'll leave you to it.
[Ink Workshop]
This glue is brilliant.
It's rare and amazing indeed.
Grandfather,
can this glue be used to blend with ink?
Of course it can.
Jingdong,
Zhen,
go invite your Third Grandfather Chen,
Grandfather Qi Chun,
and President Hu over here.
Let's work together
to make Liuhe Ink.
Grandfather,
I'd like to invite someone else as well.
You want to invite Ugly Granny over?
Yes.
Yesterday, she gave me
all of Luo Ink's manuscripts.
The ink-blending techniques
recorded in them truly amazed me.
I heard that when she was young,
be it identifying ink
or ink-blending,
her skills were as good as yours
and Third Grandfather Chen's.
So,
I want to invite her over
to help our Li family.
She gave Luo Ink's manuscripts
t-to you?
Exactly.
Jingdong,
it's your call whether you
want to invite her over or not.
Eighth Uncle,
no matter how narrow-minded I am,
I wouldn't let personal feelings
interfere with serious business now.
Zhen,
go ahead and invite her over.
I'll go invite Third Master Chen
and the others.
Then I'll get going.
Let me go do it.
You barely slept last night.
Go get some rest.
Master Luo.
Zhen,
I see he's quite strong.
Would you like
to stay
and help me?
I'm
at your disposal, Eighth Master Li.
Go invite her over.
Follow me.
Eighth Master Li,
let me go get a doctor for you.
Don't bother.
I know my condition
better than anyone.
Eighth Master Li, why did you
ask me to stay?
Master Luo,
I had you stay
because I want to talk about
what's between you and Zhen.